宮殿に向かって 近いほうから順に
By airship, it will take three days to reach... When do we leave? Today! Right now!
出口も　玉座の間に向かって 近くなっている。
Yeah, no objection from me! Understood. Then, I'll order tickets.
ああ
And the family has really high hopes for me...
レオル様が　やたら褒めるから いいかなって思ってたけど
But I can't stand it.
除念って大変。
Who wants to have their life
planned out for them?
この　お腹も 相手能力の威力次第で
Killua...
どんどん大きくなるみたいだし。
What's with the long face, Gon?
大失敗。
We'll be in the Republic of
Padokea by morning.
女のコにとって　体のラインが 崩れるの　一大事だもん。
You'll see Killua soon enough. Yep!
ねぇ　シドレ？
We'll definitely take Killua back with us!
下級兵で　珍しく言葉が 分かるから重宝してるけど…
A x Dangerous x Watchdog
あんたさぁ　もう少し 話に乗ってくんない？
Gon, Leorio, and Kurapika have arrived
見つけたら 即刻　射殺して構わん！
in the Dentora region
人民の列に紛れていても 異国民で目立つはずだ！
of the Republic of Padokea, where Killua lives.
一体　何の目的で… おい！ んっ？
There it is. The base for this family of
assassins is on that mountain?
ここで　ケータイ使うなって 何度も言ってんだろ！ 耳がキンキンいって 頭痛がして来んだよ　その電波！
It sure looks creepy... Yes. Once we reach our destination, we should start gathering information. Okay.
内容も分かるがな
Kukuroo Mountain?
次　見つけたら 腕ごと　ケータイをぶち折るぞ。
In that case, you should take the
scenic mountain bus tour over there.
い…　いや　重要案件を いくつも抱えているんだ。
The tour only runs once a day,
but you'll have a guide
こればかりは 大目に見てもらわんと。
to show you around.
フン　逃げた女を捜すのが 重要案件か？
Okay... Thank you for taking the
Lamentation Tour today.
フフフ…　俺なら見つけ出せるぜ？ ほ…　本当か？ 俺は　いろんな意味で 鼻が利くんでな。
We will be visiting Kukuroo Mountain, home to the famous Zoldyck
family of assassins.
女が身に着けてたものがあれば 追跡可能だ。
Look.
俺も評価してる。
They obviously aren't tourists.
まっ ギブアンドテークで行こうぜ
Yes...
お互いのためにな。
Everyone?
わ…　分かった！
Please look to your right.
今　持って来るから待っててくれ。 フフフ…。
That is Kukuroo Mountain,
where the Zoldyck family lives.
俺は　影の王になる！ そのために篭絡すべきは 王ではなく　ビゼフ！ テレパシー ウェルフィン様 警戒があります
A forest surrounds the 3,722-meter mountain, and the Zoldyck estate is
somewhere on that mountain.
テレパシー 用が急です
But no one has ever actually seen it.
チッ… 下級兵の信号も頭痛いぜ
The Zoldyck family includes ten members:
これは タラゲッテの血の臭い 奴の血痕と汚れた靴
a great-grandfather, grandfather,
grandmother, father, mother, and then, there are five children.
侵入者!?
All of them are assassins!
足跡が残るのを懸念して ここで　脱いだとすると 賊は宮殿の　さらに内部にいる
Then, let us approach the mountain.
時間のロスを避けた？
That's really something.
１週間前の雨の日か…
This is the front gate of the Zoldyck estate.
タラゲッテの行方が分からなくなった 日時と　一致するな
Also known as the Door to Hades
こいつに消されたのは まず　間違いない
because no one who's entered
has ever returned alive.
しかし　それならば
To enter, you must pass through the door
タラゲッテを連れ去ったのに 靴だけ残したことになる 周囲に血痕は　ない
beside the security checkpoint. But the area beyond the gate
is private property, so we can't proceed.
この場で何かにくるまれて 移動したとすると
Hold on! This is the front gate?
あらかじめ 道具を準備してたってこと
The mountain's all the way over there! Correct...
兵士誘拐が任務？ ならば　その狙いは？ くそ…　分からん！
The Zoldycks own Kukuroo Mountain, as well as the surrounding land.
シャウアプフに 助言を請うか？ いや…　俺が直接　捕まえて 吐かせりゃいい
This whole area is their backyard? Hey, guide... Yes?
やはり… 宮殿内部へ向かっている！
Little boy, were you listening
to my explanation? Uh-huh. But...
ビゼフの女より　こっちが先か
If you go inside, you'll never get out alive!
テレパシー お前らも　ついて来い！
Assassins live inside.
)
Just a photo of their faces is
worth a hundred million.
)
Seriously?! Damn! I should have taken a picture of Killua!
It's just another case of rampant rumors
お名前 教えていただけなかった…
masking a mundane truth.
早く　打ちたい…
Open the gate! I-I cannot do that. The master would not be pleased.
借り物の城
Ouch...
眼下に集うは　意思持たぬ人形 フフッ。
Are you okay? Yes, I'm fine.
これが 余に与えられた天命ならば… ハハハハ…！
Man... Now Mike's going to end up
eating between meals again.
退屈と断ずるに いささかの躊躇も持たぬ！
Huh?
ニャハハ　これで全員 王様に殴られたニャ。
Please...
んっ？
He's only supposed to eat at assigned times.
王が　お前の「円」　うざいってよ。
Mike!
ニッ…　そろそろ 言われる頃かと思ってたけど…。
Don't blame me if you get fat! What was that?
俺は　もう殴られたくない。
Hey, boys!
王の周りだけ 球体状に　オーラを避けます。
Get on the bus! You can leave.
これならば　私の気配で 気がそがれることもなくなります。
We're staying here. Huh?
オーラの空白となる球体を 移動するのは　不可能であろうが。
I see.
肉眼によって 余の動向を視認するなど　論外。
So you're young Killua's friends.
はっ　それは　警備の観点から 考えておりません。
I'm happy to hear that. I've worked here for twenty years, but this is the first time
ならば　余が貴様の気配に 煩わされることなく動けるのは
any friends have come to visit.
逐一　貴様に命令せねば 移動すらままならぬと こう申すのか？
Since I work here, I shouldn't say this, but the place is rather lonely.
「円」での警戒は 宮殿の外側だけにしろ。
Though we do see a lot of those...
明日の選別までなら それで我慢してやる。
Well, a family of assassins is pretty unusual.
不満か？
So I suppose it's the price they have to pay.
外部からの警戒ならば それで十分であろう。
Anyway, I'm glad you're here.
それとも　すでに 内部に　賊がいるとでも申すか？
Thank you. Don't mention it. However...
それでは　貴様の「円」が ザルでしかないことを
I cannot let you inside.
自ら吐露するのと同義！　違うか？ 仰せの通りです。
Didn't you see the large arm of the creature?
私の「円」では　例えば　警戒を 宮殿外部のみにしてしまうと
Its name is Mike. It serves as the Zoldyck family watchdog.
地下からの侵入者を 察知できません。
It only obeys family,
and will attack anyone else.
また　入殿を許された者の中に 賊がいれば
The beast still follows the order
それを看破できる類いの 能力でもありません。
its master gave it ten years ago...
それは　コムギのことを 言っておるのか？ いえ　他にも
To kill every single intruder.
宮殿内には１１名の兵が 残っておりまして
But technically, he isn't following the order.
彼らに関しては 宮殿内外の出入りは
Because he keeps eating them...
原則として自由です。
Anyway, I can't let you inside.
入殿時に　一応 本人の確認はしますが 仮に　敵によって 操作されているとしたら
I wouldn't want to reduce young
Killua's friends to skeletons.
その判別は　極めて困難です あとは…。
Sir, how is it that you're safe?
もう　よい！ 「円」は　宮殿内部の１階までだ！
You go inside, correct?
それならば　地下からの侵入にも 対処できよう！
If you never needed to enter,
you wouldn't have a key.
２階以上には 誰も来るなと伝えろ！
Quite perceptive of you.
くせ者が来れば 余が自ら始末してくれるわ！
But you're only half right.
余が呼ぶまで　貴様らも同様！
I require no key to get inside.
侵入すれば　狼藉と見なす！
This key is for intruders.
もともと　他のアリは
A key for intruders?
２階以上は　出入り禁止に しているから　いいとして…。 俺は　一体 どこにいりゃ　いいんだ？
For some reason, eighty to ninety percent of intruders
attempt to use the front gate.
２階と１階をつなぐ 中央大階段ですかね。
If I don't open the gate for them, they'll try to break it down.
地下からの侵入者がいた場合も そこなら対応しやすいですし。
Such troublemakers...
それにしても 王は最近　不機嫌だな。
So we added a locked door to one side.
やっぱ　軍儀の負けが 相当　悔しいってことか。 ニャ。 いら立ちの根…
The intruders take the key
from the helpless guard, and then Mike eats them.
おおかたの予想は　つく
A locked door...
私の能力 「スピリチュアルメッセージ」ならば それは　より明確になろう
That's it! As you just realized, I'm not a guard.
しかし　それは 王に対する　最大の侮辱行為
I merely clean up after Mike. And the actual gate isn't locked!
いや…　それは　言い訳…
Exactly.
正直に言おう
What?
私は　恐れているのだ 今　王に芽生えているものが この上なく　不安で
Hunter Vocabulary
恐ろしくて　たまらないのだ
Lamentation Tours
何かあって　侵入を諦めたか？ それとも 目的は達成したのか？
I've tried pushing and pulling,
but it won't budge!
いや　何か能力を使ったのかも
Are you sure it isn't locked?
おっ！
You just aren't strong enough. That's absurd!
一応　伝えとくか。
I've been using all of my strength!
お前ら　２階に行ったら 王様にマジで殺されるぞ。 宮殿内の他の連中にも言っとけ。
Just watch.
翼！ 賊が空を飛ぶ能力を 持っていれば　どうだ？
This gate's official name is the Testing Gate.
あの靴と　においはミスリード
Anyone who cannot open this gate
宙に浮いて ２階に向かうことは可能！ ユピー殿！ あぁ？ いや…　いやいや
is unqualified to enter the Zoldyck estate.
なら　なぜ　賊は 階段下まで来られたんだ!? ユピー殿。 あっ!?　何だよ。
As you just saw, the door closes automatically, so you'll want to run in, the second it opens.
ピトー殿が 「円」を解いたことはありますか？
You don't need to worry about Mike.
雨の日！ そう…　１週間くらい前です。 何だ　知らなかったのか？
He has orders not to attack any who
enter through the Testing Gate.
大変だったんだぞ。
Still, this is getting tougher as I age...
王様が自分で腕をちぎってよ。 んっ？ ピトーが　それを治している間は
But they'll fire me if I can't open the gate, so I need to keep in shape.
プフが代わって 「円」をしてたけどな。 プフ殿の「円」の範囲は どれくらいでしたか？
I should mention that each of gate
one's doors weighs two tons. Two tons?
知らねえよ　そんなこと。
You're not supposed to be able to open that!
ピトーと同じじゃねえの？
Wait, what did you say?
いや　違う…
Gate one?
プフの「円」は 恐らく　この階段の辺りまで
Yes, have a look.
賊は　そのオーラを見て ２階に行くのは諦めた…
There are seven gates.
ここまでは　いい 問題は賊の目的！
When you go up a gate, the weight doubles. Doubles?
そして　現在　まだこの周辺に
The number of gates that open depends
潜伏しているかどうかの２点 ここで　ユピーに言うべきか？
on the amount of strength you use.
いや　それは　ない 報告するなら　ピトーかプフ できれば　プフが望ましい
Incidentally, when young Killua returned, he opened gates one through three.
さらに　できるなら 賊の目的だけでも
Gate three? That would be twelve tons!
はっきりさせとく必要がある
Sixteen tons, Gon.
でないと結局
Do you understand now?
賊は運良く宮殿内まで 侵入できたが
This is what's required just
to get in the door.
プフの「円」を見て　ビビって 帰りましたで終わっちまって
They live in a completely different world.
俺の勲功は　ゼロになる
Hmm, I don't like it.
賊の目的は 俺が　でっち上げてもいいが
Mister, lend me the key.
そいつが　もし捕まれば ウソがバレるし
I came here to see my friend,
not to be tested.
かといって 思わせぶりな情報だけ与えて
You can consider me an intruder.
賊が見つからず　護衛軍に 無駄な労力を使わせたら
So let me borrow the key. I'll use the intruder's door.
俺の心証も悪くなるしな…
Gon! Hey...
チッ！ またビゼフのケータイか!?
It doesn't matter if you
won't loan me the key.
名案ゲット
I'll just climb the wall, if that's what it takes. Don't be stupid, Gon!
ってわけで賊は 俺の部下をさらって行った。
Didn't you see that monster?
レオルによると　そいつには 瞬間移動の能力があるらしい。
Its arm was bigger than your entire body! I won't accept this!
恐らく　女は奴らの仲間。
Why would you test your friends?
一緒に　テレポートしたと 考えていいだろう。
I'll never enter through that door.
くそ…　しかし 一体なぜ　そんなことを…。
You are absolutely right.
あぁ　問題は　そこだ。
However, forcing your way
through is impossible.
だが　奴らの目的も俺が見破った。 何だ？
Mike will kill you. I agree.
宮殿爆破計画！ フン　ウソ
We have plenty of time. Let's figure out a way to
enter through gate one.
待て。 んっ？
It's no use.
慌てるな　報告は爆弾を 見つけてからでいいだろ？
He's not gonna change his mind.
そんな悠長な！
Indeed...
冷静に相手の立場になって 考えてみろよ。
Unfortunately, I cannot lend you this key.
えっ？ 爆破するなら 王が確実に宮殿にいる時。 それは　いつか？
I will not feed young Killua's friends to Mike.
全人民が集まった時！ すなわち　大会開始直後！
Well, please wait here for a minute.
そこには　５００万の人間 まさに絶景！ それを見下ろす快感！
Hello? This is Zebro.
影武者だけに見せるのは 惜しいと王は思う。
Three of young Killua's
だからこそ　自ら　そこに立つ！
friends are here to see him.
敵が　そう予想するのは ごく自然だろ？ 確かに
Yes. Yes, I'm sorry. Yes. Yes.
将軍の横で　私も 何度も見ているが　あれは
Yes, I understand. Yes. I'm very sorry. I apologize for disturbing you.
性交とは全く別の えも言えぬ快感
Yep, I got in trouble. You called the mansion?
開会まで　まだ半日以上ある。
No, I was speaking with the
Zoldyck family butler.
奴の足跡を俺の鼻で追えば それまでに 爆弾を見つけるのは　たやすい。
All communication with the mansion
must go through the butler.
実物を持って報告に行けば
It's very difficult to reach any
of the family members.
護衛軍への印象が まるで違って来る。
Could you call him again?
王の恩人となれば　手のひらを 返したように感謝されるぜ。
I'll talk to him this time. Sure, I guess...
なっ！ 確かに　確かにな。
But you won't enjoy the experience.
爆弾を見つけたら すぐに連絡する。
Yes, this is the butler's office.
うん　分かった。
I'm Gon, one of Killua-kun's friends.
フン… 小心者が　ようやく 平静を取り戻したか
Is Killua-kun there?
ヘッ…。 築いて行くぜ
Killua-sama has no friends.
７分前だ。
Yes, this is the butler's office.
決行１分前にコールするから 出口に集まってくれ。
How could you possibly know that?!
それまでは　待機！
Put Killua on the phone!
そして　再び息を止めると同時に １回　肩を叩く。
Let us pretend that Killua-sama happens
to have a friend named Gon. There is no proof that you are Gon.
フン…　限界まで 我慢しなくていいからな。
If you put Killua on the phone,
he'll recognize me! By your voice? That isn't a reliable test.
むしろ　余裕を持って 息継ぎに専念してくれ。
If you put Killua on the phone,
he'll recognize me!
「神の共犯者」が発動しない間は
That was a simple recording.
安心して　俺に任せてりゃいい。 んっ？
And there are many other ways
to mimic a person's voice.
無理しねえで １本吸ったら　どうだ？
There are only a few methods by which you could perfectly mimic
someone's appearance.
奴らの嗅覚をナメちゃ 一発で命取りだぜ。
But it still isn't impossible.
タバコの残り香で 追跡するのも朝飯前。 １回目の息継ぎの瞬間 ＫＯされても　不思議ねえ。
Additionally, it's possible that someone
forced you to approach Killua-sama for sinister purposes.
ボスが突入と同時に 煙幕張るから　大丈夫だって。
As long as the threat exists, I cannot let you meet with Killua-sama.
だと思うが　リスクは　なるべく 排除しておきたいからよ。
The Zoldyck family practices the
trade of assassination.
くっ…　後悔したくはないからな。
Naturally, it has made enemies.
護衛軍が少し動いた
As butlers, our duty is to guard our masters from their enemies.
正門の上に３匹集まって 何か話し合っていたな。
I apologize, but please leave.
プフは空中散布に戻ったから
Hey! Gon!
特別な何かが 起きたわけではないと思う。
Gon!
また動きがあれば伝えに来る。 ああ　ギリギリでも 構わないから情報は　くれ。
He's really pissed now. He's going to climb over the wall... What?
これで護衛軍が 宮殿にいないってパターンは
Hey! Stop it, Gon! It's okay. You two can wait here.
ほぼ　なくなったな。
I'll go by myself.
ほぼ… まだ　完全にじゃないんだ
I can't let you do that! I'll be fine! No, you won't!
まぁ　１００％ 王と奴らは　近くにいるよ。
Both of you should calm down! I'm perfectly calm!
それは言い過ぎ。
Come down here, Gon!
もっと他の場合に 気持ちを備えてねえと
Don't be stupid.
ハプニングで体　動かねえぞ。
Gon-kun, I'll give you the key.
お前は　奴らの忠誠を 知らねえから　そう言うけど
You can go through the door. Hold on, pops!
ねえんだって！　そんな場合は！
We can convince Gon to stop!
王がいれば　側近も すぐそばに　必ずいるんだよ！ だから！
Really? But he appears to be a stubborn boy.
そう思っててもいいから 違う場合も頭に入れとけって！
To make amends, I'll accompany you through the door.
具体的にどんな場合だよ！
Huh?
あるとすれば　女だな。
may recognize me and decide not to attack.
んっ？ えっ？ 王の目的の１つが繁殖だろ？
Though I'm almost a hundred percent
certain that he'll kill us all.
宮殿内で王が何やってんのか 疑問だったが…。
You can't do that. I don't want to cause you any trouble.
子づくり！　これで決まりだ！
No, I'm coming with you.
なるほど。
The result will be the same if I stay behind.
それなら王が護衛軍を 寝室から遠ざける可能性も あるには　あるっすね。
If I send young Killua's friends to their deaths, I'd never be able to face him again.
もしかしたら　ビゼフが女性を 調達したのは　王のためかも…。 うわ！
If you die, I will also die.
パームが…　王と!?
I understand now.
計画に変更は　ない！
I didn't stop to consider your situation.
仮に　パームが どんな状況にいようとだ。
Sorry.
ゴンは　分かってねえだろうな
He's a good boy.
突入前に 気付いてよかったな
He's willing to quell his own anger
for another person's sake.
覚悟なしで　そんな場面に ぶち当たってたら フリーズ確実 分かったろ。
He believes in his own strength, as well as in his friends.
いくら考えても 考え過ぎなんて　ないんだよ！
He has a strong heart.
きっと　まだまだあるからな 想定外の状況。
It's likely that Mike
won't frighten him at all.
そう… まだ何か引っ掛かってる
You must like animals, Gon-kun.
ゴン。 んっ？
Yeah. Just as I thought.
分かってるな？ パームのことはパームに任せろ！
Did you grow up playing in the countryside?
どんな場面でも ピトー１匹に集中しろよ。
Yep! How did you know?
うん。 引っ掛かってるけど… 女か　どうかは置いといて
Gon-kun, I'm going to open
the Testing Gate again.
第３者の存在ってのは いい線だと思う
I want you to see Mike for yourself.
ちょっと待てよ。
Hey...
それは　あくまで お前達の推理だろ？
Is it really okay for us to come in? Yes, you'll be safe because you
entered through the Testing Gate.
ああ　でも　それ以外 考えられないってのは認めただろ。 お前　言ってること矛盾してるぞ。
Mike! Come here!
自分を許せない時か…。 妥当な推理だな。
Gon-kun, do you understand now? This is a trained hunting dog.
しかし　そこから 導き出される王の性格は 無機質な暴君ではなく 誇りを持つ為政者。
It's nothing like the wild animals
you're accustomed to.
確かに。
You must have expected to be able
to communicate with him.
プライドを守るために 痛みを避けないタイプ。
Until you saw his eyes.
だとすると　俺の経験上 そういう奴は　意に沿わぬ説得には 決して応じない！
Mike is currently memorizing the appearances and
scents of humans he's never seen. There's nothing else on his mind.
トップが折れない限り 護衛軍も　また同じ。
He's like a machine.
戦闘以外の選択はないと 覚悟して行けよ！
Gon-kun, could you fight him?
うまくモラウに まとめられちゃったな… でも違うんだ
No, I'm scared. I don't want to fight him!
王の自傷行為　第３者の存在
He's such an honest boy.
この仮定から紡がれる正解が まだ出ていない
Well, how long will you be here? Until we meet Killua!
そんな予感 その答えの意外さが 最悪の場合
We won't leave before then!
俺達の計画を 全て狂わせそうな… 時間だ。
Then please come this way.
くそ！　時間がない
The Testing Gate... And Mike...
１０秒前から　カウントを始める。 行くぞ　お前ら…。 腹くくれよ!!
No matter what difficulties awaited him, he would find Killua in the end.